cognitiveseo.com 2018-06-30

# Privacy Policy - cognitiveSEO

## Privacy Policy

#### as of 20th May 2018

### We will NEVER sell your personal data to anyone.

**cognitiveSEO enables the visitors of its site,[cognitiveseo.com](https://cognitiveseo.com/), to be in control of their personal data. We also provide controls that allow cognitiveSEO’s users/customers to have control over the privacy of personal data that is registered by our service. This Privacy Policy provides information about how cognitiveSEO processes and protects this data. **

cognitiveSEO considers data protection and privacy to be of paramount importance. We never sell personal data and we carry out all processing operations in strict compliance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”) (specifically but not limited to Article 6(1)(b) to (f) and Article 28) as well as the Laws of Romania (together the “ **Applicable Law** ”), where cognitiveSEO is incorporated. 

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person; an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person (the “ **Personal Data** ”). 

### What kind of Personal Data is processed and for what purpose?

_Usage Data_  
When you visit our site we store the name of your internet service provider, the website from which you visited us from, the parts of our site you visit, the IP from which you visit, the date and duration of your visit, and information from the device (device type, operating system, screen resolution, language, country you are located in, and web browser type) you used during your visit.  
We process this usage data to facilitate your access to our services (e.g. to adjust our services to the device you are using), and to recognize and stop any misuse. We also process usage data in an anonymized form for statistical purposes and to improve our site 

_Cookies_  
cognitiveSEO uses cookies to process information including standard internet log information and details of the visitor’s behavioral patterns upon visiting our site. This is done to provide you with a better experience, and to facilitate the use of certain functions. Cookies are small data files transferred onto computers or devices by sites for record-keeping purposes and to enhance functionality on our site. cognitiveSEO stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. cognitiveSEO does not process this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user.  
Cookies are stored on your individual device and you have full control over their use. You may deactivate or restrict the transmission of cookies by changing the settings of your web browser. Cookies that are already stored may be deleted at any time. Should you visit cognitiveSEO’s site with cookies deactivated, you may possibly not be able to use all of the functions on our site to the full extent. 

_Contact with us via email_  
On our site you have the opportunity to contact us to ask us questions, for example via the contact form, we ask you for your contact information (e.g. name, email address etc.). We use this data solely in connection with answering the queries we receive.  
If you receive emails from us, we may use certain analytics tools, to capture data such as when you open our email or click on any links or banners our email contains. This data helps us to gauge the effectiveness of our communications and marketing campaigns. 

_cognitiveSEO Account_  
When you sign up for and open an account with cognitiveSEO, or sign up for content or offers, we may ask you to provide us with information such as your name, email address, password and details about your organization. As otherwise detailed in this Privacy Policy, we will solely process this information to provide you with the service you signed up for. Please refer to our Terms of Service for further details on registering and using the services offered by cognitiveSEO. The data submitted should not include any sensitive personal data, such as Government identifiers (i.e. social security, driving licence), medical records or particulars connected with applications for care or treatment associated with private individuals. You may deactivate your cognitiveSEO account and/or unsubscribe from receiving content or offers from us at any time. Following termination of your account, we may retain your personal data (in part or in whole) in order to meet any regulatory and reporting requirements for the timeframes stipulated by law and in order to be able to address customer service issues. 

### Access and Disclosure to Third Parties

We use a select number of trusted external service providers for certain technical data analysis, processing and/or storage offerings. These service providers are carefully selected and meet high data protection and security standards. We only share information with them that is required for the services offered and we contractually bind them to keep any information we share with them as confidential and to process Personal Data only according to our instructions. 

We will only pass your data on to third parties without your express consent if we are obliged to do so by statutory law or an instruction by a public authority or court as outlined in our Terms of Service. 

### We want to Communicate with You

We may occasionally send you notification emails about updates to our product, legal documents, offer customer support or marketing emails. Except for cases where we are required to do so by law (e.g. notifying you of a data breach), you shall have the opportunity to unsubscribe from receiving these messages free of charge. 

### Your Data, Your Rights

You have a right to be informed of Personal Data processed by cognitiveSEO, a right to rectification/correction, erasure and restriction of processing. You also have the right to receive from cognitiveSEO a structured, common and machine-readable format of Personal Data you provided to us. 

We can only identify you via your email address and we can only adhere to your request and provide information if we have Personal Data about you through you having made contact with us directly and/or you using our site and/or service. We cannot provide, rectify or delete any data that we store on behalf of our users or customers.  
To exercise any of the rights mentioned in this Privacy Policy and/or in the event of questions or comments relating to the use of Personal Data you may contact cognitiveSEO’s support team: [support@cognitiveSEO.com](mailto:support@cognitiveseo.com). 

Where you have provided consent, you may withdraw it at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of the processing that was carried out prior to withdrawing it. Whenever you withdraw consent, you acknowledge and accept that this may have a negative influence on the quality of the cognitiveSEO Site and/or Services. You further agree that cognitiveSEO shall not be held liable with respect to any loss and/or damage to your Personal Data if you choose to withdraw consent. 

Where Personal Data is processed for the above purposes on the basis of cognitiveSEO’s legitimate interests, under the GDPR, you may object to such processing at any time. To do so please contact : [support@cognitiveSEO.com](mailto:support@cognitiveseo.com). 

In addition, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the data protection authority in the Romanian jurisdiction.

### Duration of Processing

We will store your usage data until such time when you withdraw your consent for us to do so. All other data as specified above will be retained for as long as is necessary for the purpose(s) for which we originally collected it. We may also retain information as required by law. 

### Newsletter and marketing emails

An unsubscribe link should be included in every newsletter and marketing email sent by you.

### Email tracking

Without systematically doing so, we may analyse and track the click rates and the number of emails sent which you open to assess performance rates on your emailing campaigns.

### Data Ownership

cognitiveSEO uses third party vendors and hosting partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology required to run cognitiveSEO. All analysis and data collected through the cognitiveSEO platform is owned by cognitiveSEO and licensed to its customers on an as-needed basis. 

### Security

Within the framework of its services, cognitiveSEO attributes the very highest importance to the security and integrity of its customers’ personal data.  
Thus and in accordance with the GDPR, cognitiveSEO undertakes to take all pertinent precautions in order to preserve the security of the data and, in particular, to protect them against any accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, corruption, unauthorised circulation or access, as well as against any other form of unlawful processing or disclosure to unauthorised persons.  
To this end, cognitiveSEO implements industry standard security measures to protect personal data from unauthorised disclosure. In using industry recommended methods of encoding, cognitiveSEO takes the measures necessary to protect all information connected to personal data.  
cognitiveSEO does not store credit card data.  
Moreover, in order to avoid in particular all unauthorised access, to guarantee accuracy and the proper use of the data, cognitiveSEO has put the appropriate electronic, physical and managerial procedures in place with a view to safeguarding and preserving the data gathered through its services.  
Notwithstanding this, there is no absolute safety from piracy or hackers. That is why in the event a breach of security were to affect you, cognitiveSEO undertakes to inform you thereof without undue delay and to use its best efforts to take all possible measures to neutralize the intrusion and minimize the impacts. Should you suffer any loss by reason of the exploitation by a third party of a security breach, cognitiveSEO undertakes to provide you with every assistance necessary so you are able to assert your rights. Moreover if, by some exceptional case, the direct loss incurred arose due to fault or gross negligence by cognitiveSEO, you will be able to seek compensation within the limit of liability referred to in our Terms of Use.  
You should keep in mind that any user, customer or hacker who discovers and takes advantage of a breach in security renders him or herself liable to criminal prosecution and that cognitiveSEO will take all measures, including filing a complaint and/or bringing court action, to preserve the data and the rights of its users and of itself and to limit the impacts. 

### Revisions to this Privacy Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most current version of this Privacy Policy will govern our practices for collecting, processing, and disclosing personal data. We will provide notice of any modifications by posting a written notice on our site. 

If you have an account with us, we will notify you of any material modifications by sending you an email to the email address associated with your account unless you have unsubscribed from all email communications. Your use of the site and/or Services following the effective date of any modifications to the Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of the Privacy Policy, as modified. All changes to this Privacy Policy automatically take effect on the sooner of the day you use the site and/or services, or 10 calendar days after they are initially posted on our site. Your use of the site and/or services following the effective date of any modifications to this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of the Privacy Policy, as modified. 

_GESKIMO SRL_  
_Bld. Tutora Nr.1, Bl.V1,Sc.B.et.7,ap.32_  
_Iasi, Romania, Europ_  
_support@cognitiveseo.com_
